[Music]
foreign
serving of blueberries can help mediate
the arterial dysfunction induced by
smoking a cigarette
they investigate the effect of a single
serving of frozen blueberries on young
Smokers smoke a single cigarette and the
ability of your arteries to relax
naturally drops 25 percent within two
hours
but eat two cups of blueberries a
hundred minutes before and that same
cigarette caused less than half the
damage demonstrating that a single big
serving of frozen blueberries could
counteract the artery dysfunction
induced by smoking
however of course it should be noted
that blueberry consumption cannot be
considered a means of preventing Health
consequences due to smoking this can
only be realized by stopping smoking or
even better not smoking in the first
place
two cups of blueberries is a lot though
yeah you could easily chug those down in
the Smoothie but what's like the minimum
dose we didn't know until a group of
British researchers decided to put it to
the test to enable them to do a
double-blind study they had to create a
placebo-controlled fake blueberry drink
so they used a freeze-dried wild
blueberry powder to give people the
equivalent of three quarters of a cup of
fresh blueberries one and a half cups
one and three quarters about three cups
or four cups
They concluded blueberry intake acutely
improves artery function in an intake
dependent manner
okay
so what's the optimal intake after the
placebo nothing happens but after eating
one and three quarters cups worth of
blueberries a big spike in artery
function Improvement within just one
hour of consumption
and that seems to be where the effect
maxes out less than a cup is good but
between one and two cups seems better
with no benefit going beyond that in a
single meal
can you cook them like what if you put
them in a blueberry pie or something the
same remarkable Improvement in artery
function baked into a bun just spiking
an hour later since solid food passes
more slowly through your stomach
and then if you eat blueberries week
after week you get chronic benefits too
in terms of reduced artery stiffness and
a boost in your natural killer cells
which are one of your body's natural
first lines of defense against viral
infections and cancer
uh but wait a second how can blueberries
have all these amazing effects if the
anthocyanins the blue pigments and
blueberries performed to be the active
ingredients hardly even make it into our
system
women were given more than a couple
blueberries to eat and they couldn't
find hardly any in their bloodstream or
flowing through a urine
here's what's called a chromatogram with
the spikes showing all the little
anthocyanin Peaks and blueberries here's
your blood before eating blueberries
obviously no signs of the pigments after
one hour you start to see them appear
and a few hours later they become a bit
more distinct but all in all just a few
billionths of a gram per milliliter show
up so either anthocyanins are extremely
potent and therefore active at low parts
per billion blood concentrations or
somehow their bioavailability has been
underestimated so researchers decided to
radioactively tag them and Trace them
throughout the body what happens is that
blueberry pigments are metabolized by
our liver and our microbiome the good
bacteria in our gut into these active
metabolites that are then what's
absorbed into our system so it's kind of
a team effort to benefit from berries
and that would solve this mystery as
well anyone noticed this second spike in
benefit over here at six hours how does
that make sense well some of the
metabolites peak in the bloodstream
within an hour but others ramp up more
slowly especially if the berries have to
make it all the way down to the colon
and it's not just spikes at one hour and
six hours if you track them out even
further some go up even more so like a
day later you may still be experiencing
very benefits as our gut bacteria
continues to churn out goodies that get
absorbed back into our system feeding us
as we feed them eating blueberries can
so feed our good bacteria that's like
taking a natural probiotic a win-win all
around
oh
foreign